Spencer Martel

Geospatial Technologies Professional

Spencer.martel4@gmail.com 1-(514) 653-6387





Geospatial professional with an exceptional background in programming for data-processing. Interested in remote sensing, implementing GIS strategies for climate-change responses, and geospatial software development.

Project Portfolio

Vineyard Site Suitability

Published December 2022

Utilized Python, Google Earth Engine, and Streamlit to create an interactive web experience evaluating and comparing Canadian wine terroir. Cleanly handled complex geospatial data to provide the user with a digestible analysis of results based on local data processing methods.

B.C. Wildfire Visualization

Published August 2022

Implemented leaflet in a command line tool to visualize and compare wildfire activity in British Columbia from 1950 – present. Used CSS, HTML to style elements and provide user with data regarding a fire's intensity and coverage.

Concordia Schedule Buddy

Published October 2021

Leveraged Concordia's Open Data API to build a scheduling program for students to plan their semesters. Has been live & facing 10,000+ students for 15+ months.

Experience

Manager, Melk Bar a Café, Montreal, QC. December 2018 – Present

Manage staff and ensure team building in a fast-paced, high-pressure environment. Maintain inventory, manage orders, teach serving and pouring techniques. Ensure standards of quality were met

Cellar Hand, Roche Wines, Penticton, BC June 2018 – November 2018

Supervise the wine making process from picking to bottling & ferments are proceeding properly. Report detailed information to supervisors to create appropriate action plan. Provide educative wine tours of the cellar to the public.

Education

2019 - 2023

Concordia University

B.A Geography, Geospatial Technologies

2018 - 2018

Wine & Spirit Education Trust

Level 2 Award in Wines

Technologies

- GIS (ArcGIS Pro & QGIS)
- Python
- Remote sensing
- JavaScript
- Google Earth Engine
- SQL
- Flutter

Affiliations

- Streamlit Student Ambassador
- Student Tutor
 - Remote Sensing
 - Advanced GIS
 - Programming for geospatial technologies
 - Programming for environmental sciences

Spencer Martel

Professionnelle en Technologies Géospatiales

Spencer.martel4@gmail.com 1-(514) 653-6387





Professionnel du secteur géospatial ayant d'expérience exceptionnelle de la programmation pour le traitement des données. Intéressé par la télédétection, la mise en œuvre de stratégies SIG pour les réponses au changement climatique et le développement de logiciels géospatiaux.

Portefeuille de projets

Terroir Canadien

Publié en décembre 2022

Utilisation de Python, de Google Earth Engine et de Streamlit pour créer une expérience web interactive évaluant et comparant les terroirs viticoles canadiens. Traitement propre de données géospatiales complexes afin de fournir à l'utilisateur une analyse digeste des résultats en fonction des méthodes locales de traitement des données.

Feux de Forêt en C.B.

Publié en août 2022

Mise en œuvre de leaflet dans un outil en ligne de commande pour visualiser et comparer les feux de forêt en Colombie-Britannique de 1950 à aujourd'hui. Utilisation de CSS, HTML pour styliser les éléments et fournir à l'utilisateur des données concernant l'activité d'un feu.

Copain d'Horaire Concordia

Publié en octobre 2021

Exploité l'API de données ouvertes de Concordia pour créer un programme de planification des semestres pour les étudiants. Le programme reste est en ligne et fait face à plus de 10 000 étudiants depuis plus de 15 mois.

Expérience

Gérant, Melk Bar a Café, Montréal, QC. Décember 2018 – Présent

Gérer le personnel et veiller à la cohésion de l'équipe dans un environnement où le rythme est rapide et la pression élevée. Maintenir l'inventaire, gérer les commandes, enseigner les techniques de service et de versement. S'assurer que les normes de qualité sont respectées.

Caviste, Roche Wines, Penticton, BC Juin 2018 – novembre 2018

Superviser le processus de fabrication du vin, de la cueillette à la mise en bouteille, et veiller à ce que les ferments se déroulent correctement. Rapporter des informations détaillées aux superviseurs pour créer un plan d'action approprié. Offrir au public des visites éducatives de la cave.

Éducation

2019 - 2023

Université Concordia

B.A Géographie, Technologies Géospatiales

2018 - 2018

Wine & Spirit Education Trust

Diplôme de Niveau 2 en Vins

Technologies

- SIG (ArcGIS Pro & QGIS)
- Python
- Télédétection
- JavaScript
- Google Earth Engine
- SQL
- Flutter

Affiliations

- Streamlit étudiant ambassadeur
- Tuteur Étudiant
 - Télédétection
 - SIG avancé
 - Programmation pour les technologies géospatiales
 - Programmation pour les sciences de l'environnement